Once the recording has now started,
I am admitting everybody on in who is in
the waiting room.
And so good morning everybody.
And again,
we are just starting the meeting and
letting people on in from the waiting,
from waiting in the lobby.
And so please give us just a moment for
everyone to join on in this is the Dosage
Administration and Clinical Practice
Committee.
I'm Doctor Dominic Serlo and I am with
the New Mexico Department of Health and
we are here in order to help from an
administrative standpoint with this
meeting.
The meeting chair is Ian Dunn.
And with that, oh and just as a reminder,
because we are reporting this,
Please remember to keep your language to
be appropriate as this will this will be
posted up to our website for public
viewing.
And other than that,
I turn it now on over to the chair,
Ian Dunn.
Ian, the meeting is yours.
Good morning everyone.
Thank you for taking time out of your
Monday morning to be here.
My name is Ian Dunn,
I'm the chair of the Dosage
Administration and Clinical Practice
Committee.
Today we are going to be going over still
our clinical roles tighten to fit within
that rulemaking to just kind of define
what the responsibilities of the
different roles would be.
It's just building off of what we have
been working on so far in regards to how
we're going to set up the clinical roles
and as well as the preparation.
So with that in mind,
I will go ahead and turn over to the
department to mute and unmute while
everyone gives an introduction on who
they are, their relation to dosage,
administration and clinical practice and
any affiliations.
And then please raise your hand at this
time if you would like to participate in
the meeting,
you can also introduce yourself in the
chat.
Kate, I haven't enabled your microphone.
Good morning, everyone.
This is Kate Hawk.
I'm in Santa Fe and I've been a
practitioner trauma therapist for 40
years,
done all sorts of work with psychedelics
including harm reduction and ketamine
assisted therapy.
And currently I've been working with
Scottsdale Research Institute in Arizona
doing last week we did the group of 8
veterans with FDA phase one psilocybin
mushroom research.
So I'm really interested.
I think we're,
we're looking at very important things
today.
Some of these things it's easy to just
have a discussion and and I'll be in
agreement on what the right answer is.
But all the roles and qualifications of
people who are going to do this work are
really important.
So glad we're here today.
Thank you.
And Chris, I've enabled your mic.
Good morning, everyone.
Chris Pisguski here,
Veteran Hero Carts Ambassador and
facilitator in Colorado.
And I'm just happy to be here.
Thank you.
And Brenda, I've enabled your mic.
Good morning, everyone.
It's good to see everybody here.
I am Brenda Burgard,
I am Chair of the education and training
for psilocybin for the medical program
here.
Hey,
thanks for all coming here and I hope we
have a really great meeting today.
Thanks, Denali.
I've enabled your mic.
Good morning, everyone.
It was great to see some of you in the
rulemaking hearing on Santa Fe last
Friday.
My name is Denali Wilson.
I am the state director of strategic
support for the Healing Advocacy Fund,
which is a nonprofit that supports state
programs for psychedelic assisted therapy
with a focus on access and equity.
Thank you.
And Sky, I have enabled your mic.
Good morning, everyone.
I'm an investigative journalist covering
the ongoing coverage of the legalization
of psilocybin.
I've been very excited for the progress
everyone's making and I'm just so blessed
to be here.
Thank you with the Santa Fe Reporter.
All righty.
And that appears to be everyone.
Thank you all for participating.
Jorge,
if you would go ahead and share the
clinical roles document.
Perfect.
So you guys should recognize this
document.
It did go out.
So let's just go ahead and go through it.
So an important note before we define any
of these,
a single qualified individual should be
allowed to fulfill multiple roles where
scope, training and credentialing allow.
So clinician as defined and you'll notice
I had actually reversed the practitioner
and clinician that did not match as well
with the NMAC.
So they are now back to how we started,
which was clinician and then practitioner
versus the document that went out.
It's a minor phonetic change,
but in terms of what's actually here as
defined in NMAC 7.35, point 2.
7 should be a licensed clinician acting
within their scope of practice who has
diagnostic authority.
So their responsibilities are to identify
potential candidates based on qualifying
conditions,
certify qualifying condition for entering
into the program,
and to share relevant diagnostic and
clinical history with patient consent and
in accordance with applicable privacy
laws.
Limitation certification does not
constitute clinical clearance,
not responsible for determining medical
appropriateness,
and recommendations to education and
training are to establish minimum
education, continuing education,
and licensure requirements and define the
required competencies.
So just starting off with that,
how are we feeling?
Any questions, comments,
concerns or things that we can discuss?
Kate, Hi, Yeah,
I just want to have clarity on the
pathways in which people can find their
access to this program.
Like could it be through their primary
care physician or do there have to be
some specialized identified clinicians
here?
I guess the primary care physician could
be a licensed clinician.
So that's,
that's a very broad label it for
clinicians and just want to make sure I
understand that.
Yeah.
So this could be their primary care
provider,
it could be their primary therapist.
Anyone with diagnostic authority really
could be the referring clinician to just
say, hey,
they have this diagnosis and the board
and department have decided that this
could be beneficial for them.
And then that's kind of where they would
stop.
I did see Dominic raise his hand,
so he might have additional clarification.
Thank you, Ian,
and that was why I raised my hand.
So Kate, this in this regard,
this would be similar to the way the
medical cannabis program acts.
And this is to help keep that licensure
on a federal level separate with regard
to enrollment in the program.
And what this would simply do is the
licensed clinician who has that authority
in their scope of practice would be able
to refer those patients,
essentially saying that they have the
qualifying condition and that the
qualifying condition allows for them to
be entered into the program.
And so, yes, this could be primary care,
this could be someone else.
It does not necessarily have to be
someone who has specialization.
However, we are going to want to ensure,
and this is a part that is down in the
lower portion,
that they do have some education and
continuing education with regard to
psychedelics, specifically psilocybin.
And it will be something that these
individual clinicians will have to
register with the department to to show
that they have those qualifications.
OK.
I yeah,
I guess I've got a question about that
because this is really about making sure
they have a qualifying condition as a
diagnosis.
And of course,
we'd like all the clinicians to
understand how psychedelics are being
offered here.
But I'm just wondering if that's even
necessary or if anybody could just talk
to their, you know,
whoever they're already seeing.
Yeah,
the the idea would be is that the
providers should have at least a minimum
of education,
especially because the majority of
educational programs for providers right
now do not include information about
psychedelics or very minimal.
So we just want to ensure that they would
have a minimum amount of education and
that includes things such as continuing
education, Cmes, that sort of a thing.
And so those are some of the
recommendations that education and
training will need to determine.
OK.
So say somebody just goes to their doctor
and nurse practitioner,
they're already seeing and they're
interested in this.
Then that person would have to refer them
to another person who if they if that
person didn't have these that continue
education,
they would need to find somebody who did
and and then refer that person.
Yes,
just like any other specific condition.
That is correct.
OK.
Thank you.
All right.
And then Catherine, good morning.
Something that I think we might want to
consider is adding an acronym before
clinician so that it's specific to this
program like psilocybin Medical Act,
you know, PMA clinician,
I see that under practitioner,
which I know we haven't gotten there yet.
You do specify psychedelic.
I just think we need to have some kind of
a qualifier that specifies that they're
part of this very specific program and
that that then qualifies that they've
taken whatever educational content we're
going to require of them to make sure
that they've got the bait,
the basics like what Kate was mentioning
that they have.
Yeah, something like that.
Just something where we're adding yeah,
that that would work.
Certified a psilocybin certified
clinician.
Just something that specifies the program.
Thank you very much.
Yeah and I am totally up to any like
verbiage changes.
So if someone has something better than
psilocybin certified clinician,
please do let me know.
But I did see Denali's hand up.
Hi, OK, I'm,
I'm might have gotten a little lost there.
So I,
I think I thought that the referring
clinician,
if that's what we're calling or the
certifying clinician,
it did not have to be within the program,
the scope of the program,
because the practitioner was but right.
Like,
so if to Kate's question about primary
care, right?
Or, you know,
if we're thinking more in the behavioral
health lens, right, you're established,
long time established therapist for
individual therapy or psych for Med
management.
These are people that you're already
interacting with that might not be within
the scope of the program,
but know that it exists and could make
the make information available about the
program.
But I, I had, I had before that question,
I had AI had another question about how
this is going to interact with our end of
life providers and just the the
difference of diagnosis being maybe a
little too limiting within that space,
right.
If there is a need to build out a
separate,
a separate care model or referral model
or whatever,
we end up calling this guideline,
these guidelines,
understanding the end of life isn't a
specific diagnosis, but right.
Like maybe it be that the person is
already receiving palliative care or
there were some good ideas in the end of
life committee meeting that happened last
week in in Albuquerque.
So maybe someone with more expertise
there could help map out if,
if this would be limiting,
I guess that's the first question.
And if so,
what the what the flexible solution would
be to make sure that this works in end of
life?
Yeah.
So to answer your first question or
second question,
I deferred most clinical responsibilities
assigning pretty much they end of life
care committee has full jurisdiction over
that diagnosis recognizing that it is
substantially different from the other
conditions.
So I in my view and I may have I have
designated all of that to them because of
their differences in how they're gonna be
treated.
But in terms of can you remind me what
your first question was again, I'm sorry.
Yeah, sorry.
I know that that's always the trouble if
a compound question.
I just was looking for clarification.
I think Catherine had some ideas in the
chat too of whether this first clinician,
right,
the first touch point in the system,
whether that person does need to have
does need to specifically be a part of
the DoH program.
Or if you know,
kind of like I think about maybe an
example is made medical aid and dying,
right.
You have a lot of you have a lot of
people in this ecosystem in New Mexico
care ecosystem who know that that exists
do not provide the services,
but are providing information about the
services.
That's kind of how I was imagining this
role.
But I think if we're requiring them to
specifically be certified,
maybe there's another administrative like
departmental reason that that's necessary,
and I'm just looking to understand that
better.
Yeah.
So in my mind,
I hadn't imagined it being like a super
complex or tedious process to become like
a silocyte and certified clinician.
In my mind,
it was very similar to the medical
cannabis program where they have to get
registered so that they have access to
Biotrack and can submit their
applications,
but not necessarily a full scope.
But I will hear more from Dominic.
I think he has more clarification.
Yeah.
And actually Catherine really expressed
it very clearly and very well.
It's along the same same lines of what we
had discussed even in previous things
that we just want to ensure that these
clinicians have some understanding that
they, they know who, you know,
the patients,
that they're referring them into a
program and what the program is really
about.
We're not talking about it being a
lengthy,
long process such as what facilitators
and other individuals have to go through.
And you know, either Colorado or Oregon.
We're really talking about you have a
couple of hours of either continuing
education or a class and it could
potentially even be simply a, you know,
an online asynchronous sort of a training
that's provided.
And then we,
but we have to determine exactly what
those requirements are,
but not looking at lengthy long term
investments on the provider standpoint
about having to go through multiple
courses and things like that.
But we need to ensure that they at least
understand a little bit about psilocybin
and what they're actually, you know,
certifying these patients for with
enrolling into the program.
It is not very different than what we are
doing.
We're not looking at a high bar on it.
We're really looking at,
does this clinician understand and
correct Denali,
not facilitated facilitation training.
Simply do you understand what psilocybin
is about the potentials for your patients
before you're just, you know,
certifying them for the program as far As
for having a condition for the program.
So hopefully that helps.
Yeah, perfect.
And then I see Sky.
Hi, good morning.
I'm a little confused but I really
appreciate Kate and Denali and
Catherine's remarks regarding physicians.
When I as a person read psilocybin
certified clinician to me it doesn't say
primary care doctor and I understand that
they that all primary care physicians
should be versed in what psilocybin is.
I agree with that and it should be a
really short program for them to just get
to.
My brain's not working this morning.
I'm so sorry get familiarized with what
this is.
On the other hand, I really,
I really believe that it would help if
primary care was included with clinician
because if I go to the doctor and I say I
have ABC going on and he turns around and
says, well, you know,
you might want to consider,
consider psilocybin and he tells me all
about it.
I don't really view him as a clinician.
I view him as my doctor.
So then he would then refer me to the
program who then goes through a
psilocybin certified clinician to get
certified for the practitioner.
It just seems to me as the person on the
other side and trying to finish this
article that it,
it could be a little more clear.
Can I get thoughts on that?
That's really my question, yeah.
So I'm not too strict on like semantics.
So psilocybin certified clinician could
be changed to just clinician.
That's how it's written in the
administrative code.
However,
we just wanted to recognize that there is
a little bit of training before they're
able to refer to the program.
They should know what the program is
before they're sending patients there.
It's not meant to imply that they are
providing the psilocybin services
themselves.
In my head,
how I had always imagined it was,
you're already going to your therapist.
Your therapist had done their
registration process and then you would
just get deferred to a psilocybin,
you know specialist area that would
actually handle administration and that
kind of thing.
That way that provider,
let's say it is a primary care provider
and A and a physician.
That way they don't have as much fear
that the DEA is gonna take away their
license for participating because they're
just saying here,
here's what a program is,
I'll go ahead and write you in.
But a practitioner,
A psychedelic therapist will actually
take care of you.
And they are the ones primarily working
in the psilocybin space.
Yeah, I, I understand all that.
I guess.
I don't know if it's cymatics,
as you said, but I think to me,
if you you want to say clinician,
like somebody just put something in the
chat.
Please let me refer to it.
Who was it?
Some saying what a clinician could be a
primary care,
a therapist or whomever I think there may
be.
Maybe consider just spelling it out in
parentheses so people understand it.
If this is going to go out to the public,
because it's to me,
just a little thoughts,
everybody's thoughts would be great on
this one.
I'm I'm kind of a I feel like a stickler
a little bit because an MD perfect DO
perfect.
Yeah,
those things I think would help being
listed then.
Oh, OK, that's what that is.
That's all.
Thank you.
I mean, yeah, no worries.
And then Dominic, OK.
And just to clarify a little for
everybody and and Ian mentioned this.
This is really simply what these
positions are within the rule.
This is not what individuals will
necessarily call themselves or some of
those other aspects.
But for the rule,
we have to define what the role is and
part of it.
If you look at that definition,
the important part is the individual who
has diagnostic authority.
So it's somebody do with licensure based
upon their scope of practice and what
their licensing board allows,
who has diagnostic authority for these
conditions.
So it's not a laundry list of here are
all of the licensures that can allow for
it because we've been compiling that list.
And and I will say,
and we've experienced this over the years
and other programs.
Sometimes there ends up being a licensing
board for example,
where it's missed and then somebody from
that board or somebody who has that
particular license comes forward and says,
hey, this is within my scope of practice.
So we don't define that as far as doing a
big list of all the different potential
licenses in the rule.
We keep it as this is within their scope
of practice and allowed through their
licensing board,
those individuals who have the diagnostic
authority and then these different
providers can then go through the process.
And again,
if we don't have them initially on the
list,
they can show us just where we will do
that research from a department
standpoint to ensure that is accurate and
add them on in.
And so when we talk about these different
terms,
and it's the same as far as clinician,
practitioner, facilitator, a guide,
a journey person, whatever term,
this is just the term for within the rule
to define out that role.
But somebody, for example,
because we've heard from a lot of people
that say that they like the term guide as
an example for somebody who is sitting
with someone going through the process.
Other people don't like it for a variety
of reasons and they would prefer
facilitator.
Some people will prefer the term
facilitator for what we've got here
calling a practitioner.
So it really it's,
it's not so much about what individuals
are going to call themselves for the rule.
It's about the role and then how that
gets education moving forward.
Because some of these points about who
then will be able to do it,
that's going to be a part of what goes
out publicly from an educational
standpoint,
helping to work with various providers of
different licensure types of letting them
know that look,
this is within your scope of practice or
it is not within scope of practice.
And that's going to take time to develop
and to actually have out there.
So adding in these different items about,
you know,
as far as what exactly what degrees,
what licensure,
all of those sort of things like
Catherine for example,
has in the chat about a PhD for as a
prescribing Dr.
Well, that would work already,
for example,
with a licensed clinical psychologist.
So they are,
they already have the PhD and they have
the additional licensure with regard to
being able to diagnose various conditions.
And so it's thinking about those aspects,
but that for the rules,
the terms need to be very simple.
And so that's why we have these as they
are right now as proposal.
But what people want to call themselves
as they go out and they educate and they
do that,
it really is going to be dependent upon
what they like.
However, with that in mind,
if there is another specific term that
people can agree upon,
we're perfectly fine with changing that
for within the rule.
Clinician, however, is within the statute.
So that one we're leaving as is just with
regard to that first step because that is
part of the statute.
So I hope that helps.
Yes, thank you so much.
So Denali had a question or comment.
Yeah, I put a little more in the chat.
I think it might just be helpful to ask,
but if any of this language is going into
regulations to get a perspective from
your legal department about certification,
it might just be better to use permit for
the from the department's perspective in
terms of the risk that the department
takes on.
When you when you certify someone,
you're saying this, you're,
you're implying that you've evaluated
their skills as a clinician and then that
can just attach different liability.
But I think Chris in your office will
have some ideas about that.
That's all.
Thankfully a lot of.
So as long as the meat and bones is
adhered to,
the department has a lot of leeway with
the semantics portion.
So if it does come out or Chris comes out
and says that, oh,
it's not good to use that word,
they can change, you know,
certifying they don't have to follow the
recommendation down to like the letter.
They just have to follow the guidance
that it brings.
So if that does become an issue that
would probably be handled internally.
I'm not a lawyer,
so I can't speak to that,
but I do appreciate your insight.
Does anyone else have no,
like do you have a new question or
comment or is your hand just residual?
It's residual.
Oh, OK, no worries.
I can figure out how to take it down here.
Oh, there we go.
No worries.
All right,
So then we will go ahead And would there
be letters like probably not.
It would be my guess because I don't know
that would be up to the department.
But So what Sky put in chat was would
there be letters following like PCC,
psilocybin certified clinician?
I don't think so,
but I will leave that to the department.
I cannot speak for them as far as that
goes.
We're not at that point yet.
Again,
this is to establish the rule as far as
those kinds of specifics.
That's not something that we're at this
point, but it probably would not.
Again,
we don't want to complicate it more and
have people think that oh,
the psilocybin certified clinician is the
person doing the facilitation,
for example.
These are very specific duties and job
roles within there that go within the
rule and the idea is,
is to ensure that we have as broad
abilities for the various clinicians
throughout the state so that there is
good access with regard to it.
However, if for example,
a clinician wants to say, hey,
I have gone through the the training that
was required and I can certify
individuals for the program as having a
condition, then that is perfectly fine.
That will be up to those individual
providers.
Perfect, thank you.
When we move on to our next definition,
I went ahead and provided how things are
divided defined in the rules in the chat
just so that we can the definition of
this one.
I trimmed down to just be the rules
because we had a lot of deliberation.
So I wanted to give more chance to add
and to recreate instead of starting from
a full practitioner.
So the definition in the rule is an
individual who is licensed in who is a
licensed healthcare professional,
who is certified by the department to
provide medical psilocybin integrative
therapy,
supervised guides and has who has
completed department required trainings.
Does anyone else think we need to add
anything to the definition of a
practitioner?
All right,
so seeing the scope is to conduct a
comprehensive biopsychosocial assessment,
review medical and psychiatric and
substance use history,
identify contraindications and medication
interactions,
evaluate risk for adverse psychological
or physiological response and create a
safety plan and to determine medical
appropriateness for psilocybin treatment.
Our responsibilities are to evaluate
clinical appropriateness for psilocybin
use,
including but not limited to medication
interactions,
medical and mental health history and a
current functioning.
If the patient is not appropriate,
refer them to primary care provider or
other appropriate treatment.
Ave.
use trauma informed and culturally
competent communication throughout the
screening and treatment process.
Assign a clinical support tier,
establish dosing parameters or
considerations,
approve or deferred participation based
on safety.
Denali, you got raised your hand.
Hi, sorry,
I maybe I'm responding to the wrong thing,
but the the question about definitions is
the ones that you put in the chat.
Yes,
so those are the definitions in the rule
the for practitioner too.
Yes, did we define practitioner?
I think well,
maybe it would be helpful to hear from
the department.
I think my impression last week was some
of the with some of the,
some of these terms are we're not
promulgated.
They're being held as a for further
discussion because I do,
I do have feedback on these from both
like a liability standpoint and I think
there were some important conversations
that happened around the term guide.
But I just want to get clarity maybe from
the department that I I think we're
pausing on the promulgation of these
specific roles other than clinician
because that's just the statutory.
Yeah.
So just to answer that real quick, Denali,
is it what's happening is the rule is
still, you know,
depending upon what we get from the
hearing officer,
we'll still continue to move forward.
However,
in the next hearing on this specifically,
we can adjust and change them as needed.
This is the starting point.
And so that's where the questions are,
is what items potentially to change Ian's
presenting it as this is just what's in
there at the moment.
What do we need to potentially change on
it.
So that's the situation as it moves
forward.
It's that changes that in this area with
regard to dosage, administration,
training and education.
Those rules are not finalized and we
simply adjust those definitions in each
of those particular, you know,
the hearings that revolve around those.
Does that make sense?
It does make sense.
I think I,
I have kind of extensive feedback on
these definitions that I,
I don't want to derail us from.
But maybe most importantly,
I think there are both cultural
considerations that I've heard brought up
in this committee and others about the
term guide that I'd like to,
I'd like for us to have a,
a conversation about.
And then also on guide,
there are some liability implications if
we,
if we're asking a practitioner to
supervise them that I think we want,
we want to think through, but I,
I don't know if we want to have this
conversation now or maybe table it.
I think it's also relevant to the
Training and Education Committee,
but defer to the chair and department
about where best to have those
conversations.
So for now,
since we're focusing on the practitioner
portion,
if you would like to what comments you
have about that, we can begin there.
And then when you have when we get to
guide, we can get to that as well.
Yeah, Well, I, I think it's,
it's a little hard to move through
quickly because I think they're pretty
foundational about the roles of team
members, right.
And but yeah, in in general,
there are gonna be both care coverage and
professional liability issues that are
going to present major barriers to the
viability of the program.
If we establish A supervisory
relationship between a practitioner who
is a licensed healthcare provider and a
guide who my understanding of the
definition and conversations right maybe
does not need to be a healthcare a
licensed healthcare provider.
So I and,
and I think that those relationships and,
and teams that we're creating are really
important to,
to think through really carefully.
So I'm,
I'm a little reluctant to provide
feedback that feels rushed.
And yeah, I,
I know that we're having conversations,
ongoing conversations in many different
places about liability, both,
well insurance and liability,
both from a care coverage perspective and
professional liability,
understanding that these are two
foundational pieces of law that will
dramatically impact access and equity
within the program long term.
So that's my, I don't know,
kind of non feedback.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Ian.
No worries.
I do appreciate you taking the time to
point out some of those things.
On the contrary side is if we are going
to have guides be non licensed
individuals,
then what we'll have to do is find some
way to prevent wrongdoing.
And I'm not saying that liability is
necessarily the best option,
but we do need some Ave.
for a clinician or a practitioner.
They both report to their respective
licensing boards and so I can ensure that
they're they're doing most best practices
in terms of a guide because they don't
have a specific licensing board.
We want to ensure that they have someone
to report to.
That way we can always hold
accountability.
What I don't want is for someone to just
be able to get away with doing the wrong
thing either.
I'm not saying that that's like a problem
that we're foreseeing,
but I am saying maybe we do need to
consider this liability portion as well.
Sky had some comments.
Can you hear me?
OK, good.
Is this a Gray area?
This is something I wanted to ask in one
of the meetings recently.
It might have been the end of life where
we were talking about caregivers or
guides.
If facilitators and therapists and
growers all need to be trained and
licensed, how is it the guides,
and maybe I'm misunderstanding are not
under the same umbrella?
I would think it's either black or white.
You're either licensed or you're not.
So am I misunderstanding something?
No,
so they would still be licensed from the
Department of Health.
The different issue was a healthcare
provider,
when they're licensed through a licensing
board, have ethical obligations,
moral obligations,
and duties to their patient.
We can try to create those from scratch
within the department.
However,
oftentimes leaning on these existing
institutions can be beneficial.
I'm not saying that guides will have like
no training and none of that.
No,
they'll still be trained and have to be
licensed by the department.
Their only area where they are a little
bit freer is that they don't have
licensure to any board or like they don't
have a board of nursing or a board of
physicians or that kind of thing.
When I hear the term guide,
as I used to lead groups and I'm a
retired intuitive counselor,
I feel it's someone taking you through a
journey.
That's why I asked.
Thank you.
Kate, I,
I just want clarification because you
just said that guides would be licensed
through the DoH and with my understanding
there won't be any new licensing like
what they have in Colorado.
But, you know, I'm,
I am one wondering how it can work to
have teams of people who have, you know,
licensed people or people with
specialized skills,
but not in the current, you know,
licensing system.
So I'd,
I'd like to have clarification like when,
when you just said, well,
they will be licensed,
obviously they have to be credentialed
and recognized,
but what might that look like?
So yeah,
my point was more so where the licensure
was from.
So we defer a lot more,
we give a lot more deference to licensed
providers in the grounds that even if we
don't make a specific rule to prohibit it,
we can hold a licensed healthcare
provider accountable via their ethical
and moral obligations to their patients.
When we are licensing,
we have to set every rule and strategic
trying to predict what people are going
to do wrong and then trying to prevent it
versus people that institutions that have
existed for decades.
So that's where that cut off was.
And again,
I'm not saying that that this is the way
that it has to go, but I am saying,
what if we're going to change something,
we need a, a reasonable change,
something that we can say, OK,
what is wrong here?
Because that's the only way that we're
going to kind of get through this
rulemaking process.
My point about the guides was just that
they don't have a secondary institution.
It was not that they were not licensed.
And I'm sorry if I misspoke.
OK, I'm,
I'm glad we're taking time wrestling and
I'll keep asking questions,
even if they're kind of fuzzy at this
point.
I'm,
I'm glad we're continuing with
clarification.
Are we moving on to the guide section or
did I mean,
are we done with the the section before
that?
We're still in a little bit of discussion.
I still see one more hand up and then we
can go ahead and move forward.
Denali.
Oh, did you still want to speak?
Denali?
Yeah, sorry,
I UN raised my hand instead of unmuting
myself.
No worries.
Yeah, like Kate,
I'm grateful that we're we're talking
about these important details.
I put in the chat what we'd recommended
as an amendment and I,
I just want to say again that this
doesn't address.
I know and heard and appreciate some of
the concerns that were raised in other
committees about the term guide itself
and whether that's appropriate for us to
reflect.
But just setting that aside and thinking
about the the both the,
the potential risk that we are exposing
people who are taking on this role and to
clinicians and practitioners who are
interacting with this role,
the recommendation would be right.
But is, is,
is trying to respond to two kind of
concurrent problems.
1 if we if we talk about supervision,
we have potentially exposed people who
are not healthcare providers and cannot
receive medical malpractice insurance
because they are not qualified to receive
it to medical malpractice claims also
potential claims of unauthorized practice
of medicine.
So that's that's kind of really where the
supervision piece is a problem.
And I hear and really appreciate the
desire, right.
The reason that we write in supervision
isn't because we want to give people
complicated insurance problems.
It's because we want to create patient
safety.
And so I think that knowing that there
are these barriers,
we really need to lean into our,
the education that we require people to
come to complete and continuing education
to be like where safety is held.
And you know,
our compliance officers that are
operating and operating within the
department and are assessing safety and
responding and tracking adverse events.
And right we have and we've created a
system in which the department has
authority to respond to an address,
address harm.
But the supervision piece,
I think creates too much of A complicated
problem for folks who are, you know,
intending to help people access healing.
I'll say to another right to to address
what I hear, Ian,
is your desire to uphold patient safety
without creating what might be too
complex insurance and liability issues.
Maybe,
maybe 1 requirement would be this is
something we recommended to the
department as well is that,
and it's pretty consistent across spaces
is that people carry sufficient insurance
for whatever their role is.
So if you require somebody to be
operating in a space where they're
insured that right,
that the idea being that a patient is not
a patient who is harmed is not going to
be left without recourse.
Those are just the off the cuff thoughts
and ideas that I have lingering on this
issue.
All right.
So thank you.
From the general vibe,
I think we are switching over to guide,
so we will go ahead and do that as well.
Thank you so much, Danal.
Yeah, I have been reading it.
I do like the the version that you
provided in the chat.
It is it would suffice with me,
but I will listen to some other thoughts
just to make sure I'm not making that
decision, you know, unilaterally.
But Gregory.
Hey, pardon me for catching up.
I had some stuff going on this morning
and I haven't had time to, like,
put all my thoughts on paper,
but I thought we were in the camp of
steering away from using the term guide.
I know we're beholden to the language in
the bill that was passed,
and that's not gonna change.
But I was under the impression that we
were going to find a less problematic way
of interpreting that language put as we
moved into the rule of law.
I don't want to like,
drive down a massive tangent about why
the term guide might be problematic or in
or more more importantly,
like inaccurate for what our clinicians
and different types of practitioners and
facilitators are doing.
But unless you are like singing my spirit
through a trauma,
walking me through in another realm,
you are not a guide.
You are some physical person in a room
that's going to make sure that my life
signs are OK.
And then if I need to talk to somebody
when I come back, there's somebody there.
But if you're not like, I mean,
I don't mean to get too esoteric,
but if you're not like actually guiding
my spirit through like Hades or wherever,
like like we're,
we're appropriating some not even
language, just like a,
a type of action that can happen in the
psychedelic realm.
And forgive me if I don't think I,
I deeply respect this program and I very
much care about how it proceeds.
But let's ask the questions before we put
this in print.
All right?
And then Dominic had some clarification.
Yeah.
So I, I,
I've mentioned this a few times and in
other committees we have been asking and
instead of continually having a debate of
using guide or not using guide,
what we've really asked is what term
would people like to be utilized that was
only chosen originally as a placeholder
because it seemed to,
at the time when we first started the
meetings seemed to be the term that
seemed to be most acceptable.
What I'm hearing from everybody and have
heard and have requested is what term
would be best.
We don't need to continue talking about
the problems with the term guide.
We just need to know what term to utilize
so that we can adjust that within the
rules.
So I'm going to ask now for the people
who are here,
and you could just put it in the chat if
you would like.
What term do you think would be most
appropriate for this particular position
so that we can do that in moving forward
and not continually just going back and
saying guide is a problem,
guide is a problem.
We need to know what term people would
like and we need to come with sort of
some kind of consensus on it.
So what I would say is if people can put
that in the chat, we can compile it.
And then what we can go ahead and do is
from that point we can maybe in the next
meeting or potentially even in one of the
other committees say here's a list that's
been created and sort of move forward.
I hope that helps it.
Just talking continually as far as from
the semantics isn't helping us move
forward with what we need and we just
want to make sure that this is not
something that is set in stone.
This was just something as a placeholder.
So and I am seeing facilitator quite a
bit in the chat.
I see some others including guide and
also some others within there.
So again,
we'll make a list of those from those in
the chat and let's continue looking at
what the actual aspects of what we're
asking for these positions and not be
hung up so much as far as just the name.
So thank you.
Everybody already ruffled.
No, you're good.
Don't worry.
We have to have the conversation.
I it was just I hadn't had,
we didn't cleanly transition from the
last one to this one.
I was gonna include that we can discuss
the name because I know that Chris had
brought that up at the last meeting and
we didn't quite get to it.
Yes,
given what is currently most in the chat
we will go with facilitator.
I think what could be a good idea.
Of course I can't speak for the
department is just sending out basically
all of these options there.
It looks like guide facilitator,
non clinical facilitator and clinician
assistant and just send it to the e-mail
blasts and have them vote because yeah,
the term, at least from my perspective,
the term we use is the least important
part.
The role that we assign them is far more
important.
But Gregory,
did you have additional comments or did
you leave your hand up?
Oh, cool.
All right.
And then Chris, hi and thank you.
I,
I just had one more thing on our last
role.
I,
I wonder if that person should also
evaluate, you know,
the support system and whether you know,
the person has a support system capable
of, you know,
and are ready to engage in that suocybin
treatment.
Thank you.
And then my other comment was about guide,
but I think we've,
we've kind of beat that to death now.
So perfect.
Well,
thank you for responding in the last
meeting.
I know we didn't get to that issue in
more depth to talk about it,
but I am glad that we were finally able
to bring it up.
So thank you, Chris.
Catherine, yes,
what concerns me about this is I'm seeing
that the practitioner doesn't do any
preparation and that the facilitator or
guide, whatever we want to call that,
is doing all the preparation.
That doesn't feel right to me.
There's two types of preparation.
There's administrative preparation and
there's psychological preparation.
And the counselor or the licensed
practitioner very, very,
very much needs to be a part of the
psychological preparation because that
involves going over their trauma history,
making sure they understand what to
expect, making sure that they know what,
what to, you know,
like managing expectations,
helping them understand, you know,
to lean into the experience,
all that stuff.
Whereas administrative preparation is
more like, you know,
where it's going to be,
how long it's going to take place.
You know, there needs to be kind of both.
I'm actually going to get,
I don't know if it'll let me put a photo
in the chat,
but I presented on to the education
committee about the difference between
these and how we need to have both
administrative and psychological prep as
well as administrative and psychological
integration.
And I think that that just very much
needs to be included in the practitioner
piece.
So I'm going to go ahead and see if I can
post that picture now.
Yeah,
I went ahead and updated practitioner to
where did I just put it that they must be
involved in psychological preparation.
And then I changed in facility,
in facilitator.
It's conduct administrative preparation
sessions in coordination with the
psychedelic therapist.
Is that kind of what you were envisioning
or do I need to change the language?
Let me see that.
So yes, and integration, right.
So preparation,
I think you already had integration in
there,
but I just want to make sure that we're
also keeping that within the scope of
practice, meaning that, you know,
the facilitator isn't going to be doing
the psychological prep,
they're going to be doing the
administrative prep anyway.
Just want to make sure that those those
are clarified and people understand that
those are two totally different things.
So conduct administrative preparation and
integration sessions in coordination with
the psychedelic therapist.
Perfect.
Yes.
Cool.
All right.
And then Gina?
Tina,
your mic has been enabled and mute
yourself when you're ready.
Sometimes.
Sheena,
if you're able to log on and off and or
also if we can put the phone number in
the chat.
If that doesn't work, we can call in.
You can also type in your comments into
the chat, if that's helpful.
And then while we are waiting for her to
type up her comments, Chris,
So just going back to what Catherine said.
And I'm, I'm not sure I, I disagree,
but I,
I just want to have a little bit of
discussion around that.
Like the, the practitioner could also,
and probably would be a facilitator as
well.
And and in that they are assigning the
how do you have it termed up there?
You say they assign the clinical tier,
right.
And so I think for less complicated cases
the the facilitator might be able to
handle all that prep work,
but that's just just something I wanted
to bring to the table.
Yeah.
And I think that that would actually go
in line with what Catherine said.
So the comparison of like what is on a
list and if we're looking at their
history would be administrative prep.
It's checking one list against another
list.
And then that the actual like
psychological goals, intentions,
sentence setting that would be done by a
licensed like therapist or other provider.
And then from there,
that person could do both.
It's just depending on what they're how
involved they are in actually setting
like patient expectations, intentions,
and cognitive processing.
All right.
And then I'm going.
All right.
And then I went ahead and updated the
definition to be what Denali had said.
So means an individual who has completed
department,
approved training and education and has
been registered with the department and
whose role is limited to providing non
clinical support and presence to a
patient preparing for,
experiencing the effects of,
and integrating the effects of
administration as allowed by the program.
A guy does not or.
Does not perform,
and shall not be construed to perform
clinical assessment, diagnosis, treatment,
or any other act constituting the
practice of medicine, nursing,
or other licensed health profession.
A guide does not act under the
supervision,
direction or authority of any licensed
healthcare provider,
and no provider shall be deemed to have
supervisory responsibility over a guide
solely by virtue of their concurrent
participation in any part of the program.
Cool.
All right,
I will go ahead and paste the Ian if you
would.
Also there's a comment in chat about
changing guide back change guide to a
facilitator in the bottom of the
paragraph.
Those last appearances of guide.
Yes, here,
let me just it's in there twice.
Cool, there you go.
Thank you and thank you for pointing that
out Denali.
I had not seen that there was still
remnants, so I do appreciate that.
Cool.
So let me go ahead and paste this in the
chat.
All righty.
So with this whole document now I'm just
going to ask if there's any more
discussion questions,
things that they believe need to be
changed,
any other discussion to be had about
these clinical roles?
All righty,
then we will go ahead and take a vote on
the clinical rolls.
All those in favor of adopting the
clinical roles as posted in the chat and
appears on the shared screen,
please raise your hand at this time.
Again, there's a comment.
Can I sit with this is a is a question by
Greg in the chat.
So what we can do realistically,
not too much changed.
So I'm just going to go ahead and move
forward with a vote on the discussion.
We've been, we just went over it.
So I'm gonna still proceed with the bow.
If you are in favor of adoption of these
clinical roles,
please raise your hand at this time.
Three hands, Perfect.
And then please lower your hands at this
time.
Kate, did you have a question?
Oh, nevermind.
Alrighty.
And then if you are against these
clinical roles,
please raise your hand at this time.
See one hand 3 to 1.
The clinical roles are adopted.
Now.
We can go ahead and move on to the
preparation part of this document.
I'm really curious to see what how we can
integrate the differences between
administrative prep and psychological
prep that Catherine had brought up
because I had not considered that at the
time of writing.
So I'm just going to give you all a heads
up that we may need to make changes.
So preparation consistent with the
Medical Psilocybin Act,
a qualified patient must be determined to
be medical appropriate for treatment by a
psychedelic therapist.
Facilitators operate within their defined
scope and do not assume responsibilities
related to clinical appropriateness,
dosing or medical safety planning.
So for the preparation sessions,
patients shall initially complete at
least two preparation sessions totaling
no less than three hours.
I believe in a prior meeting we changed
that to two.
I will keep it as three until we discuss
it more hours prior to administration.
Initially.
This limit may be reduced if repeating
dosing with each session lasting at least
one hour,
with the final preparation session
occurring no less than 24 hours and no
more than 60 days prior to administration.
Where feasible,
one hour of preparation shall be in
person.
Participation shall be conducted by a
facilitator present during administration,
and the preparation may occur via
telehealth when clinically appropriate
and shall be documented in the patient
record.
All right.
Anyone have any questions, comments,
concerns about that first paragraph,
Chris, you know,
I wonder if we shouldn't put in here that,
you know, these are kind of the,
the bare minimum requirements, I think.
And, and I'm not sure, you know, I,
I know we've kind of assigned the
clinical rules where, you know,
the the tears will be established for
patients, but, you know,
patients with complex PTSD might require
much more preparation than this.
But I don't also want to create barriers
and to access.
So yeah,
I just I wonder if it should be noted
that it is a minimum requirement,
not necessarily reflective of what should
patients should get as far as preparation
perfect.
So I went ahead and added that minimum
preparation session requirements floor,
not a ceiling is what we listed below.
And then is that kind of what you had in
mind or perfect?
All right.
And then Gregory, I think it would just,
it would be who's the program to write it
as language where the number of sessions
is deferred to the decision of The Who
went, whomever makes that decision.
And that way as things shift and change
and new roles come out,
you don't have to rewrite the rule every
single time because there might be there
may be conditions in the future that
allow for a, a brief,
A brief introduction and there could be
much more complicated sessions that
require years.
So it's just like if we constrain it here,
we box ourselves in,
but if we defer it to the broader
deciding like the qualified decision
makers that we are defining in the
previous section,
then we have more flexibility.
But just a recommendation.
Yeah.
So it would say like here's a general
standard clinical decision making can be
used to change these amounts basically is
what you're recommending.
Well, I mean,
and we decide who gets to make the
decision and we write the language that
defers that preparation time,
the pressure preparation context to the
professional who's qualified to make that
decision.
It doesn't need to be like,
we don't need to define what preparation
sessions are,
we just need to define the box in which
they're guided.
I, I,
it's just a different approach of writing
it.
Yeah, no, I could, I don't have the I,
I can work on language and send it,
send recommendation,
but that's just like the perspective I'm
coming from.
Yeah, we're more of a,
a clinical judgment side.
And I,
I do agree with widening clinical
judgment.
So let's hear from a couple of other
people.
But I do think that that could work.
Denali, Hi.
Yeah,
I think this is kind of related to
Gregory's comment.
I,
I think we have to make a decision and
maybe this is something where the
department's perspective would be helpful.
I've been operating under the,
under the assumption that some of the
care model protocols won't actually live
in rural,
but will live in departmental guidance,
which I, I think it's,
it's helpful for a couple of reasons,
because when it's a lot easier to change
as are as evidence of what you know is
best practices, you know,
we're not going to be required to go
through rulemaking process to adapt to
new evidence.
But I think whether our recommendations
here live in rural or in like internal
DoH guidelines for clinicians,
we may want to consider something that's
come up in other subcommittees of,
you know,
we have 4 very distinct diagnosis and
qualifying conditions.
And I think it's,
it's appropriate to recognize that the,
the care of each will be different.
And so to to Chris's point, you know,
maybe for PTSD,
we require more intervention.
Maybe also we consider, you know,
whether the role of a non clinical
facilitator is appropriate for every
indication or not.
I think that's,
that's an important question for us to
consider.
And you know that the department with the
input of the Advisory Board retains the
ability to add new qualifying conditions.
And what we don't want to do is risk is
create regulations that don't allow for
future indications.
I know someone in the last or maybe the,
the previous, the last,
not the last meeting,
but the meeting before that was from the
Psychedelic Pain Association.
And,
and I know a major challenge for pain
patients and trying to trying to move
through both Oregon and Colorado's
regulated systems is that, you know,
it just isn't clinically necessary for
someone who's moving,
not for a behavioral health indication,
but for pain management to have to have a
prep session before each administration
session.
That is completely different for someone
who's moving for any behavioral health
indication.
I'm packing a lot into my response,
but I think in general, right,
I want us to consider whether it makes
sense to think about best practices as
being specific to each and each existing
indication.
And then you don't have in our mind what
what the burden both on the on the
Advisory Board and department would be to
make sure that those that those
regulations or requirements reflect what
is clinically appropriate for not yet
qualified,
but likely to be qualified at some point
in the future indications.
Yeah, so I do concur,
but I will I see the Dominic has his hand
up so he might be able to provide
clarification.
Yeah, thank you, Ian.
And yes, Denali,
you are making a very clear distinction
between what would be guidance or
recommendations from the department for
best practices versus rule.
So as far as the actual treatment of
patients,
every patient is going to be a little
different.
And so, and someone said it in the chat,
I,
I kind of lost thread on it for a moment
there, but where, you know,
the actual treatment in and of itself is
really going to be up to the licensed
individual.
So the practitioners.
And so we do need to have the discussions
with regard to this so that we know what
to put forward as far As for best
practices and for guidance,
especially for people and,
and clinicians and practitioners and
facilitators who are going to be new to
this to help them and to help as far as
from a training perspective as to what is
going to be necessary and needed.
However, from a rule point,
it really just outlines here what the
essentially the job duties are.
So for example,
for the practitioner would be helping to
ensure with the care team that the care
being provided is going to be the best
possible for that patient.
And of course,
trying to convert that into a rule,
rule appropriate language is a little
more difficult than just saying it the
way I am here right now.
But that is essentially the intent.
The rule sets that framework,
but the actual treatment really should be
up to the practitioner.
So for example,
we don't turn around and say in rules and
things like that,
that for example for cardiac surgery you
must use this procedure that may change
in a year, that may change in six months.
That's going to depend on the condition
of the patient.
And so that is not the point and the
intent of the rule here to say that for
individual patients,
this should be exactly what the treatment
looks like.
We should have some guidance and some
guidelines on that,
but that part does not go in Rule.
The rule is here are what the
responsibilities of those providers,
practitioners, facilitators are,
and then the actual care itself should be
left up to that care team.
I hope that makes sense and I hope that
helped clarify a lot of this,
but the discussions still need to happen
because we still need to do that guidance.
That just won't be part of the rules
asked.
So thank you for for pointing that out as
well.
Denali.
Perfect.
And then I see Gregory's hand up.
I have no idea why that was probably
leftover.
No worries, Chris.
Oh, Catherine, yes.
I just want to kind of speak a little bit
to what everybody has been talking about
and what I put in the chat.
I actually do think that for new clients
that have never,
especially somebody who's never had this
experience before,
I think 2 psychological preps are needed
and one administration prep.
And then I also just want to kind of go
back to what was being said here.
I do think the practitioner should be the
one that makes the decision.
There are protocols out there right now
by Johns Hopkins that shows that two
doses,
macro doses can help with treatment
resistant depression and those doses can
be anywhere from.
I have one article that says 2 weeks
apart,
which is not what I would recommend,
but they could be 4 to 6 to 8 weeks apart.
And I don't think you need as much prep
for the second one as you do for the
first one.
So there's just an example.
Even just using the qualifying conditions
where I don't know if you would need,
you know,
to do 2 or 3 preps for the second journey,
which is spaced months apart,
you still will need a prep session,
but I don't know if you'll need 3.
And then of course,
as chronic pain comes on,
chronic pain is one of these things where
you're not needing as much prep as well.
So I just want to point all of that out.
I really like this idea of maybe making
it the practitioners responsibility and
then we provide offer guidance, you know,
through education as to what that should
actually look like.
So thank you.
Perfect.
And then hearing from you guys,
I went ahead and change that first part
paragraph to just be one sentence.
The amount of psychological preparation
shall be determined by the psychedelic
therapist.
Does anyone have an addition to that or I
would also just at some point we do need
to specify there should be at least one
admin prep always for the facilitator
because you always need one prep for
admin with respect to, you know,
what time of the day it's going to be
when the prep,
I mean when you know what the setting in
the set and all that's going to be
looking like.
So I think you need both.
Thank you.
All right.
So the amount of psychological
preparation time shall be determined by
the psychedelic therapist.
The administrative preparation can be
determined by this facilitator.
Does that sound good to everyone or
except that I do think there needs to be
an admin prep always.
Like I think we need to require at least
one admin prep because even if you get it
done at the same location,
you still need to go over all the things
to make sure that they're understanding
everything that's going to happen.
And I'm actually thinking the admin prep
should be, oh,
I see you put it under prep session.
So yeah, that works.
I just think we need to have at least one
admin prep.
And then the psychological prep is
obviously determined on a case by case
basis.
That's just my two cents.
Should we put like not to constrain them,
but should we put like a, a limit and say,
you know, we'll set your,
your psychological prep can be good for
90 days, but after that we need to re,
you know,
assess what your new intentions are.
How have you moved through your goals and
that kind of thing.
If it is going to be a repetitive dosing,
right?
And I think intentions and all that is
part of is should be part of
psychological prep in my opinion.
But I agree,
I think there needs to be at least one of
each before.
And actually sometimes it can be combined
if it's done by the facilitator.
There's so many pieces here to look at.
So in my mind,
what I'm thinking is like the
psychological preparation time,
I think we should do a psychological
preparation session is good for.
Administration up to 90 days post session,
post preparation and then the
administrative preparation can be
determined by the facilitator or can be
performed formed by the facility.
Could even be combined depending on the
the situation and the person.
I do think though,
this is gonna require some time for us to
process.
Just saying.
Oh, absolutely.
Yeah, OK.
We have like half an hour left.
There's no way we're making it right.
Preparation.
But just.
I just don't wanna get your words wrong
and then have to summarize it after the
meeting.
So are you thinking like at least one
preparation session before each?
At least one admin prep before each?
Here's how I think there needs to be at
least one preparation session before each
treatment.
They can be combined.
Admin and psychological can be combined,
but you do need at least one prep session
for every single treatment.
If they've already been treated before,
I think combining the two can make sense
because you're updating their intentions.
You're making sure they understand any
differences that are going to happen this
time versus last time.
So I don't know,
maybe we need to have like definitions
for first time versus subsequent times,
right?
Like because the first time I still do
think you need 2 psychological and one
admin and then subsequent you may not
need as many depending on the situation.
I don't know.
Again, a lot to think about right now.
Perfect.
And then Gregory had some comments.
I'm gonna kind of say again,
like the I don't have the language pinned
down here,
but I think that this whole section can
be two sentences.
We need to zoom out because right now
we're trying to figure out what all the
minutia and what all the different
possibilities and variant edge cases are.
That is not the job of this document in
my perspective.
Please I open argument and conversation
on that.
All of this can be handled by we need
this type of thing, this type of thing,
this type of thing.
These are the types of people that are
allowed to make that directive.
There are so many variables and we are
not not only are we not going to figure
out that in this in this session,
we are not qualified to make those
decisions like like,
like that work is down.
Well, yeah, maybe we are.
Maybe there are people in this room that
are qualified to make those decisions,
but those decisions are not really the
directive of this document, in my opinion.
It needs to zoom way out.
And that might get us through this more
easily.
Perfect.
Thank you.
And then Chris?
I'm sorry,
and I don't remember what I was going to
say.
No worries, it's Monday.
All right.
And then Catherine.
All righty.
So what we are going to do in order to
better find a way to phrase this,
I'm going to take what Catherine said and
what Gregory said and prepare a new
preparation document.
No clinical roles document will have
changed.
It will just be the preparation to adapt
to the role changes and the comments that
were made.
But I think we are at a pretty good
pausing point just because I prepared the
preparation document before the changes
to the clinical roles.
So this would give me a chance to make
sure that everything aligns and also to
add in what we have discussed at this
meeting.
Does anyone have any objection to that,
Chris I don't have any objection to that.
I I was gonna make one recommendation
though.
Ian.
Yeah.
I wonder if we shouldn't call a brief
Advisory Board meeting soon to get the
clinical rolls over to Brenda in an
approved fashion.
That way she can start working on that.
I'd hate for her to start working on it
and then it, you know,
come back to the Advisory Board and not
get approved.
What is the minimum amount, Dominic?
When would the department be available
for like an impromptu Advisory Board?
Yeah, I,
I don't know that that's necessary.
There is the Advisory Board on the 15th
and I think that that would be sufficient.
If you wanna cover it and include it on
that agenda, I would be OK with that.
Brenda,
does that work for you if you're still in
this meeting?
I do not think she is.
Then we will go ahead and keep it.
Just she is.
She is still in the meeting.
She responded yes in the chat.
Perfect.
All right,
then we will go ahead and take it up on
the 15th and then we can do a really
quick one.
I'll go ahead and transmit it to the rest
of the board following the closure of
this meeting and then we can work on
preparation.
Let's see when can we do our next meeting
calendar?
All right, so I am busy Monday the 11th.
Can you guys do Tuesday the 5th?
Any objection of that?
No, not seeing any.
All right.
Tuesday the 5th at 9:00,
if that works for the department or
you're not getting an answer from me
because my computer is locked and I can't
check the calendar.
Dominic.
No worries, Jorge.
I I was actually just logging on in and I
just give me a moment because our system
seemed to decide right at that moment to
block us all.
It's up here.
Here we go.
Yeah, it's what?
I'm back in now.
There's Advisory Board meetings.
I don't know what else the department
might have done.
Yeah.
No, no,
it looks like the Tuesday the 5th at 9:00
AM starting at 9 will work from a
department level.
We do have a meeting at 10.
So if we could do that as a shorter
meeting, do it 9 to 10,
that would work for us.
And then on that side, yeah.
And then I think because we're gonna be
stripping away a lot of the like
requirements and leaving the clinical
judgment, that should work.
So we'll go ahead and do Tuesday the 5th
at 9:00 AM and we'll get that invite out
and posted as usual.
All right, well, perfect.
Thank you guys all so much for coming.
I really appreciate you spending the
morning with us.
I appreciate all of your opinions and
everyone who spoke today.
Thank you guys so much for being here.
We wouldn't be able to do make this
program without y'all.
So thank you.
Have a great rest of your week and cheers.
Thank you everybody.
Have a great day.